<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="FmodBus" inherits="RefCounted" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Represents an FMOD Studio bus for audio mixing and effects processing.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		FmodBus represents an FMOD Studio bus, which is a mixing channel in the audio pipeline. Buses are used to group audio signals together for collective processing, volume control, and effects application.

		Buses form a hierarchy where audio from events flows through buses and their parent buses until reaching the master bus. This allows for:
		- Grouped volume control (e.g., "Music", "SFX", "Voice" buses)
		- Collective effects processing (e.g., reverb on all music)
		- Ducking and sidechaining between bus groups
		- Centralized mixing control

		Buses are defined in FMOD Studio and loaded as part of bank files. Use [method FmodServer.get_bus] to obtain bus references from loaded banks.

		Operations on buses affect all events and child buses routing through them, making buses powerful tools for dynamic mixing control.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="get_mute">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the bus is currently muted.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_paused">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the bus is currently paused.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_volume">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the current volume level of the bus. This is a multiplier where 1.0 is the original volume set in FMOD Studio.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_mute">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="mute" type="bool" />
			<description>
				Mutes or unmutes the bus. When muted, no audio will pass through this bus or its child buses.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_paused">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="paused" type="bool" />
			<description>
				Pauses or unpauses the bus. When paused, all audio processing through this bus is suspended, but events continue running.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="set_volume">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="volume" type="float" />
			<description>
				Sets the volume level of the bus. This is a multiplier where 1.0 is the original volume set in FMOD Studio. Values greater than 1.0 will amplify the audio.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="stop_all_events">
			<return type="void" />
			<param index="0" name="stopMode" type="int" />
			<description>
				Stops all events currently routing through this bus. The stopMode parameter controls how the events are stopped:
				- FMOD_STUDIO_STOP_ALLOWFADEOUT: Allow events to fade out naturally
				- FMOD_STUDIO_STOP_IMMEDIATE: Stop events immediately
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>