<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<class name="FmodParameterDescription" inherits="RefCounted" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/godotengine/godot/master/doc/class.xsd">
	<brief_description>
		Describes the properties and constraints of an FMOD Studio event parameter.
	</brief_description>
	<description>
		FmodParameterDescription contains metadata about an FMOD Studio event parameter, including its name, ID, value range, and behavioral properties. This information is used to properly set and validate parameter values.

		Parameters in FMOD Studio can be:
		- Continuous (float values within a range)
		- Discrete (specific labeled values)
		- Automatic (controlled by FMOD, like distance or direction)
		- Global (shared across all event instances)

		Parameter descriptions are obtained from [FmodEventDescription] objects and provide the information needed to:
		- Set parameter values correctly within their valid range
		- Display appropriate UI controls (sliders vs dropdowns)
		- Validate parameter values before setting them
		- Understand parameter behavior and constraints

		This class is primarily used for editor tools and debugging, but can also be helpful for runtime parameter validation.
	</description>
	<tutorials>
	</tutorials>
	<methods>
		<method name="get_default_value">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the default value of the parameter as set in FMOD Studio.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_id">
			<return type="int" />
			<description>
				Returns the unique numerical ID of the parameter. This ID can be used for faster parameter access compared to using the name.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_maximum">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the maximum valid value for the parameter.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_minimum">
			<return type="float" />
			<description>
				Returns the minimum valid value for the parameter.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="get_name">
			<return type="String" />
			<description>
				Returns the name of the parameter as defined in FMOD Studio.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="is_automatic">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the parameter is automatic (controlled by FMOD based on distance, direction, etc.) and cannot be set manually.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="is_discrete">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the parameter is discrete, meaning it only accepts specific values rather than a continuous range.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="is_global">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the parameter is global, meaning it's shared across all instances of the event rather than being per-instance.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="is_labeled">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the parameter has labeled values (like an enum). Use [method FmodEventDescription.get_parameter_labels_by_name] to get the labels.
			</description>
		</method>
		<method name="is_read_only">
			<return type="bool" />
			<description>
				Returns [code]true[/code] if the parameter is read-only and cannot be modified at runtime.
			</description>
		</method>
	</methods>
</class>